No actual Europeans were harmed in the making of this film.
EuroTrip is a comedy film directed by Jeff Schaffer.
When Scott learns that his longtime cyber-buddy from Berlin is a gorgeous
young woman, he and his friends embark on a trip across Europe.
Scott Thomas, played by Scott Mechlowicz.
Cooper Harris, played by Jacob Pitts.
Jenny, played by Michelle Trachtenberg.
Jamie, played by Travis Wester.
Mad Maynard, played by Vinnie Jones.
Madame Vandersexxx, played by Lucy Lawless.
EuroTrip is a 2004 American teen sex comedy film directed by Jeff Schaffer,
from a screenplay he wrote with Alec Berg and David Mandel.
The film was produced by The Montecito Picture Company
and distributed by DreamWorks Pictures.
It stars Scott Mechlowicz, Jacob Pitts, Michelle
Trachtenberg, and Travis Wester.
Mechlowicz portrays Scotty Thomas, a recent high school graduate from Ohio who travels
across Europe in search of his German pen pal, Mieke (Jessica Boehrs).
Accompanied by his friend Cooper (Pitts) and twin siblings Jenny and Jamie (Trachtenberg and Wester), Scotty's quest takes him to England,
France, the Netherlands, Slovakia, Germany, and Italy, encountering awkward, humorous, and embarrassing situations along the way.
EuroTrip was released in theaters on February 20, 2004.
It received mixed reviews from critics and underperformed at the box
office, grossing $22.6 million against a $25 million budget.
It gained popularity through its home video release and
eventually attained a cult classic status.
It is considered a spiritual successor to the 2000 DreamWorks release Road Trip, but was not
originally intended to serve as such, with the original title being Ugly Americans.
Before release, DreamWorks deliberately changed the film's title to
EuroTrip, in order to capitalize on the success of Road Trip.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, paris,
france, alcohol, pen pals, travel.
The tone is lighthearted.